Nick Bitzer

10371 Routt St Westminster, CO 80021 (720) 771-6094 <u>nbitzer@gmail.com</u> <u>https://www.linkedin.com/in/nick-bitzer/</u>

Profile

As a Director at Comcast, I am currently responsible for the operation, development and overall reliability of the Comcast CDN. In this position I have maintained competitive operational costs by leading a lean, focused, diligent team capable of solving even the most difficult engineering issues. After working as a software engineer for nearly 10 years, I discovered within myself a drive to help engineers find their potential and to propel them forward in their careers. Utilizing engineers' and managers' respective skills, I strive to guide my employees toward clear goals, ensuring team productivity for the overall growth and success of the company.

Experience

April 2018 - Present

Comcast, Denver, CO - Director, IP Content Delivery Network (SRE / Operations)

- Responsible for the reliability of the Comcast IP CDN, which serves more than 100 billion requests per day to millions of clients across the United States, supporting hundreds of millions in revenue for Comcast
- Managed Comcast's largest hardware deployment to date for the CDN, requiring constant clear communication across multiple organizations to ensure efficient and timely deployments
- Responsible for maintaining a close working relationship with the Product and Program Organizations
- Significantly transformed the CDN operations team toward a more modern, automation-focused SRE engineering team
- Continuous interaction with senior leadership (VPs and SVPs) in communicating current state of our product, as well as the anticipated needs and future direction of the CDN
- Responsible for recruiting and maintaining elite engineering talent, both locally and remotely
- Led the design of the first set of KPIs for the Comcast CDN to establish operational visibility

March 2017 - April 2018

PGi (via ReadyTalk acquisition), Denver, CO - Engineering Manager

- Responsible for infrastructure budget projections/adherence to multiple product lines across PGi
- Led the SRE team through a transition to a more modern infrastructure stack (from data center to AWS + Kubernetes)
- Maintain bi-weekly one-on-one meetings with all my direct reports to gauge employee satisfaction, generate candid conversations, and to foster mentorship
- Sole Engineering Manager responsible for effectiveness of two crucial software deliverables for PGi's new flagship product
- Maintain positive working relationships with fellow Engineering Managers, ensuring proper communication and expectations for respective teams' roles within the company
- Report project status to senior leadership (VP of Engineering, VP of Operations, and CTO)
 on a weekly basis
- Worked with senior engineering leadership to establish metrics-gathering and monitoring standards for the entire engineering organization

May 2014 - March 2017

ReadyTalk, Denver, CO - SDET II/DevOps Engineer

- Responsible for maintaining/enhancing the developer toolset (Jenkins, Artifactory, deployment scripts, infrastructure automation, etc.)
- Responsible for deploying the entire ReadyTalk code base (using Jenkins and Python scripts) on a six-week cadence. It was my job to make sure the code got into production without issues.

2011 - 2014

NetApp, Boulder, CO - Automation Engineer

- Designed and built an automated build, deploy, and test system from scratch. The tool
 used a Perl/PHP backend with a JavaScript/CSS/HTML front end to report build/test
 statuses.
- Directly managed multiple enterprise storage configurations, which are accessed by hundreds of developers each day running thousands of tests

2007 - 2011

LSI (contract PRO Unlimited), Boulder, CO - QA Automation Engineer

 Lead automation QA Engineer for the T10-PI project; automated a large percentage of the project's tests

Awards

1st place in the Software Testing World Cup (North America)

 https://www.prnewswire.com/news-releases/readytalk-qa-team-conquers-prelims-of-2016-software-testing-world-cup-300367120.html

Publications

Published in the http://www.SDTimes.com chronicling our journey in the Software Testing World Cup

• https://sdtimes.com/author/nick-bitzer/

Education

2012 - 2014

Metropolitan State University of Denver - Denver, CO

Studied Computer Science